<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-26T12:57:58-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Minimal Statistics Maximum Information</title><subtitle>Modern Day Data Scientistist, Breaking down concepts and .</subtitle><author><name>Love Tyagi</name><email>lk4ml@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">AI in Drug Discovery</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Drug_Discovery_Using-AI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI in Drug Discovery" /><published>2022-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Drug_Discovery_Using%20AI</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Drug_Discovery_Using-AI/">&lt;p&gt;Developing a new drug from original idea to the launch of a finished product is a complex process which can take 12–15 years and cost in excess of $1 billion. The idea for a target can come from a variety of sources including academic and clinical research and from the commercial sector. It may take many years to build up a body of supporting evidence before selecting a target for a costly drug discovery programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a target has been chosen, the pharmaceutical industry and more recently some academic centres have streamlined a number of early processes to identify molecules which possess suitable characteristics to make acceptable drugs. This review will look at key preclinical stages of the drug discovery process, from initial target identification and validation, through assay development, high throughput screening, hit identification, lead optimization and finally the selection of a candidate molecule for clinical development.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Love Tyagi</name><email>lk4ml@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Drug" /><category term="Discovery" /><summary type="html">Developing a new drug from original idea to the launch of a finished product is a complex process which can take 12–15 years and cost in excess of $1 billion. The idea for a target can come from a variety of sources including academic and clinical research and from the commercial sector. It may take many years to build up a body of supporting evidence before selecting a target for a costly drug discovery programme.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Biomedical Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Biomed_research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Biomedical Research" /><published>2022-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Biomed_research</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Biomed_research/">&lt;p&gt;Biomedical research is the broad area of science that looks for ways to prevent and treat diseases that cause illness and death in people and in animals. This general field of research includes many areas of both the life and physical sciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilizing biotechnology techniques, biomedical researchers study biological processes and diseases with the ultimate goal of developing effective treatments and cures. Biomedical research is an evolutionary process requiring careful experimentation by many scientists, including biologists and chemists. Discovery of new medicines and therapies requires careful scientific experimentation, development, and evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists continue to look for ways to reduce the numbers of animals needed to obtain valid results, refine experimental techniques, and replace animals with other research methods whenever feasible.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Love Tyagi</name><email>lk4ml@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Reserach" /><summary type="html">Biomedical research is the broad area of science that looks for ways to prevent and treat diseases that cause illness and death in people and in animals. This general field of research includes many areas of both the life and physical sciences. Utilizing biotechnology techniques, biomedical researchers study biological processes and diseases with the ultimate goal of developing effective treatments and cures. Biomedical research is an evolutionary process requiring careful experimentation by many scientists, including biologists and chemists. Discovery of new medicines and therapies requires careful scientific experimentation, development, and evaluation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Protein Protein Interaction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Protein_engineering/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protein Protein Interaction" /><published>2020-07-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Protein_engineering</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Modern_DS_Blog/Protein_engineering/">&lt;p&gt;Protein–protein interactions (PPIs) are physical contacts of high specificity established between two or more protein molecules as a result of biochemical events steered by interactions that include electrostatic forces, hydrogen bonding and the hydrophobic effect. Many are physical contacts with molecular associations between chains that occur in a cell or in a living organism in a specific biomolecular context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proteins rarely act alone as their functions tend to be regulated. Many molecular processes within a cell are carried out by molecular machines that are built from numerous protein components organized by their PPIs. These physiological interactions make up the so-called interactomics of the organism, while aberrant PPIs are the basis of multiple aggregation-related diseases, such as Creutzfeldt–Jakob and Alzheimer’s diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PPIs have been studied with many methods and from different perspectives: biochemistry, quantum chemistry, molecular dynamics, signal transduction, among others.[1][2][3] All this information enables the creation of large protein interaction networks[4] – similar to metabolic or genetic/epigenetic networks – that empower the current knowledge on biochemical cascades and molecular etiology of disease, as well as the discovery of putative protein targets of therapeutic interest.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Love Tyagi</name><email>lk4ml@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Drug" /><category term="Discovery" /><summary type="html">Protein–protein interactions (PPIs) are physical contacts of high specificity established between two or more protein molecules as a result of biochemical events steered by interactions that include electrostatic forces, hydrogen bonding and the hydrophobic effect. Many are physical contacts with molecular associations between chains that occur in a cell or in a living organism in a specific biomolecular context.</summary></entry></feed>